Quite a bit of snow falling up on those mountains still
I think until 1600 meters or so, still snow
that’s around 4500ft.
Yeah, it's a cold week.
I think it's going to rain almost every day.
So I'll be working inside, mostly.
I'm on my own. Ela is still away for her own projects
I'm going to be pointing in the wall,
which is slow work on my own,
and maybe also do some, electricity already
And pull some lines and connect
some lights.
Yeah.
And I have to finish the outside work
that I did the last two weeks.
But with the rain, it's
better to wait a bit because
If I get a heavy trailer of gravel.
It's going to sink away in the mud I think
but we'll see.
water for better bonding
Picked up new solar panels.
These ones are going to be replaced.
They're about 15 years old, I think.
So they're...
it's going to be quite an upgrade.
Those are 230W and these are 455.
And they're also bifacial.
So they can charge
from the backside as well.
And that will be beneficial on the the ones that are on the back standing up.
When there’s snow in winter.
That will reflect some light onto it
or give some extra charge.
But mostly the front is already
just a big upgrade.
They are slightly larger, in dimensions,
so I have to rebuild the stands
and also just space them out slightly
and a little bit higher for winter.
So it's easier with clearing snow.
I’ve already been rewiring a few panels.
I'm connecting all of the panels
to these PV combiner boxes.
which kind of minimizes the, the amount of MC4 connectors
because I was using those MC4 branches
to connect everything together,
but at some point
they started to melt and deformed.
it could be some dirt
or a bad crimp, some resistance that they get too hot.
So this is better.
Some breakers built in as well, some protection. So,
there’s going to be another one,
but most of the work
will be just rebuilding the stands
because the panels are slightly bigger, so
it needs to be rebuilt.
So I'll show the whole overview of the installation
once we're finished.
in two weeks.
The bumblebee is confused,
They're always digging holes in between the stones.
They do that on the outside here,
where it's easier
because it's a soil, like a clay mortar
But now that the walls are pointed,
you can get it in anymore.
So it's interesting to see.
Yeah, I made a good leap with the pointing of the walls,but it's it's dirty work.
My hands are incredibly dry.
Although I wear gloves all the time,
but, I think two more days, one more day pointing,
so a bit of this side wall
and then the front half,
and then that's done.
I remember from the first cabin that it was a big job
takes a few weeks.
But yeah.
Almost there.
And then, then the floor work,
then cleaning up outside,
doing some more soil
work, filling the trenches.
They're still open.
But I'm waiting for some drier days
as well.
May is always very rainy here
as well as this week,
but quite beautiful.
Dramatic skies of clouds coming in.
Yeah.
My brother's
visiting next week with a friend
Ela will be back.
So I think we'll do a lot of work next week
Well, the week after probably
Probably
because we take some days off as well.
Yeah.
Some problems at the chicken coop...
The fox is there.
I mean,
I have shots of him in the night, and,
he's trying to get in and you can see it.
Because there's more digging underneath
the chicken coop.
He's trying to dig a hole underneath.
But he won't be able to
because the chicken wire is going
all underneath the soil,
so there's no way to come through.
But he's persistent.
There wasn't an attack, actually,
this week.
I didn't film it because...
Well, it happened very fast.
It's not on camera,
but I was having lunch inside.
I heard the chickens making noise.
So I ran up very quickly.
And then I saw the fox disappearing
in the forest with the brown chicken.
But he let it go eventually,
and she was looking quite ruffled up.
I think she lost a bit of her comb
the red bit in the middle.
But she's all right.
But the fox is there.
So even now, in broad daylight,
he is, trying to get in.
And during the day,
I often let them out in the outside run,
which is not protected.
Like the fox can just jump over the fence.
So, yeah, that's,
That's something
The first year, it was just, they were out every day roaming about.
And there was never a predator,
never an issue.
Only with, some domestic dogs
that were off leash.
That gave some problems in the weekends.
But, yeah, maybe an electric fence
could fix this problem.
I'm keeping them inside now.
And just a few times
a day, I'm just staying there,
letting them outside, and,
But I have to stay there
because otherwise the foxes
probably couldn't get them.
So. Yeah,
that’s a new thing.